CESAR SANCHEZ-VEGAS

Senior Solutions Engineer

832 – 439 - 3705



Cesar.sanchezvegas82@gmail.com



Atlanta. GA



linkedin.com/in/cesarsanchezvegas



PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Highly motivated and experienced pre-sales executive with a proven history of achieving targets and delivering results. Full-Stack Developer with experienced in system engineering and systems integration. Excellent with presentations while continues engagement pre and post-sales with shareholders and customer.

SKILLS

PROFESSIONAL

Full-Stack Developer

Excellent Problem-Solving abilities

Excellent Communication Skills

Strategic Planning and Management

Coach and Trainer

Vendor and Partner Management

Great Analytics Skills

WORK EXPERIENCE

SOLUTIONS ENGINEER AND LATIN AMERICA SALES EXECUTIVE VSoft Corp | Duluth, GA | 2016 - Present

- Answer Request for Proposal and create Business Proposals,
 Statements of Work and any other documents required during the sale cycle for VSoft Core Banking and VSoft Check Processing initiatives.
- Perform Gap and system architecture analysis on Core Banking systems such as Fiserv-DNA, Fiserv-Portico, Finastra-Sparak, Corelation-Keystone, and other Core, report finding and create a new proposed system architecture to prospect customers during the sales cycle.
- Prepare and perform sales presentation and demonstration to prospect and existing customers on VSoft Core Banking system for US activities and on VSoft Check Processing Platform for all LATAM activities.
- Perform analysis in the designing, defining and documenting the VSoft Remittance Solution, VSoft Real-Time Signature Verification, VSoft Positive Pay, DNA RTP integration through Kony and direct AFS integration.
- Define requirements (BRDs, SRDs, etc.) to integrate with customers and partner solutions either through API Calls, SOAP, REST web services or extract files.

BRANCH MANAGER, VP

JPMorgan Chase Bank N.A. | Atlanta, GA | 2014 - 2016

- Managed daily operations of a \$60 million branch banking facility, including developing strategies to increase deposit and investment balances, managing the monthly budget and recruiting/retention of employees (six).
- Consistently exceed goals and expectations in all measurable categories while growing balances by 25% YOY.

CESAR SANCHEZ-VEGAS

SKILLS

TECHNICAL

New Business Development Territory Expansion

Executive Presentations

Competitive Market Positioning

Account Management

Client Needs Assessment

EXTRAS

LANGUAGES:

Fluent in English and Spanish

EXPERIENCE CONTINUED

- Evaluated branch performance and implement actions to ensure objectives were met while strengthening and growing customer relationships through a commitment to quality service.
- Trained team to focus on Customer Satisfaction improving behaviors, which has resulted in the branch being among the top 10% in customer service satisfaction nationwide (Q4 100% Satisfaction)

ASSISTANT BRANCH MANAGER, AVP

JPMorgan Chase Bank N.A. | Atlanta, GA | 2010 - 2014

- Managed, coached and developed sales and service team to maintain an operationally sound branch (total NOL for three consecutive years – the lowest in the market.)
- Executed and provided guidance on sales activities with sales and service team helping increase balances and referrals.
- Consistently among the top 10% YOY in customer service satisfaction.

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

BRANCH MANAGER
ASSISTANT BRANCH MANAGER
FINANCIAL SERVICE REPRESENTATIVE
SunTrust Bank | Atlanta, GA | 2008 – 2010

EDUCATION

CODING BOOTCAMP CERTIFICATE: Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, GA

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap,
Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

MASTER OF SCIENCE IN FINANCE: Georgia State University, Atlanta, GA

B.B.A. IN ECONOMICS: Georgia State University, Atlanta, GA

B.B.A. IN FINANCE: University of Houston/Downtown, Houston, TX